<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DevOps on Gerundium</title>
    <link>https://gerundium.github.io/devops/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DevOps on Gerundium</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://gerundium.github.io/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>5.1 Overview</title>
      <link>https://gerundium.github.io/devops/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gerundium.github.io/devops/overview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;State/Version: &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20250405&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;51-overview-&#34;&gt;5.1 Overview 💡&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DevOps in the context of Kubernetes, along with tools like Flux and ArgoCD, can be described as a modern approach to managing infrastructure and application deployments that emphasizes automation, collaboration, and continuous delivery.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;💬&#xA;Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re managing a Kubernetes cluster for a large organization. You decide to adopt GitOps to streamline your deployments, and you start with &lt;strong&gt;FluxCD&lt;/strong&gt;. Flux is great—it monitors your Git repository, detects changes in your Kubernetes manifests, and applies them automatically to your cluster. It ensures that your cluster&amp;rsquo;s state always matches the desired state defined in Git. You feel confident because everything is automated and version-controlled.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5.2.3 Argo Events</title>
      <link>https://gerundium.github.io/devops/argoevents/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gerundium.github.io/devops/argoevents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;State/Version: &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20250405&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;523-argo-events-&#34;&gt;5.2.3 Argo Events 💡&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Argo Events is an event-driven automation framework designed for Kubernetes. It enables triggering workflows or actions in response to specific events, such as changes in Git repositories, messages in a queue, or HTTP requests.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-features&#34;&gt;Key Features&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;➕ &lt;strong&gt;Event Sources&lt;/strong&gt;: Supports a wide range of event sources like webhooks, S3 events, Kafka, and more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;➕ &lt;strong&gt;Event Processing&lt;/strong&gt;: Uses sensors to process events and trigger actions, such as starting Argo Workflows or updating Kubernetes resources.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
